







EDWIN HERRERA

PROFILE

Seasoned IT professional, with more than 20 years of experience in the Information technology industry, holding management positions for the last 12 years. I have occupied leading roles with direct responsibilities on networking, virtualization, server hardware, desktop support, Windows OS, Active Directory, Microsoft Exchange, software quality control, VOIP, IT security, Datacenter, telecom, databases, ITSM, IT operations monitoring, and others.

Expertise in the creation of IT department structure, the formation of well trained and highly motivated teams, process improvement, IT best practices implementation, Standard Operation Procedure creation and IT infrastructure and processes transformation to obtain PCI certification.

EXPERIENCE

VP of IT Operations 2018-2019 **ERC (Enhanced Resource Centers)**

- Provided strategic direction and oversight to the Database Administration,
 Engineering, Application Support, and ITSM groups.
- Maintained a motivated IT workforce with the appropriate mix of business knowledge, technical skills and competencies to ensure the core IT functions were reliable, stable and efficient.
- Developed and maintained a consistent IT Change Management Process that increased the successful implementation of all changes on the company IT systems.
- Worked along the Infosec department to support our security certifications (PCI and HIPAA).
- Developed and maintained key metrics reports about IT systems and processes, to guide the company in the IT strategic decision making.
- Lead the implementation of Standard Operating Procedures across IT teams to guarantee a consistent execution of the IT operations.
- Lead the development and implementation of a new software patching process that ensured a consistent software upgrade life cycle on the company IT systems.

VP of SDLC 2016-2018

ERC (Enhanced Resource Centers)

- Provided oversight to the software development operations of the company.
- Research and development of innovative new technologies to achieve business goals. Some of the innovative ideas brought and implemented were:
 - First company Learning Management System that later became the ERC University that is used to train all company employees.
 - Biometric physical access control across the company.



- Biometric Self-Service Kiosk for password resets.
- Lead development and implementation of intracompany chat and broadcast communication system that helped provide a more secure internal communication channel between employees.
- Lead research and development of first-generation web virtual assistant, to demonstrate the potential cost savings of this technology via customer self-service transactions.

Chief Technology Officer 2011-2016

ERC International (Formerly Laurus International)

- Provided oversight of all IT aspects of the company. Established the technical vision that aligned with the company's business goals.
- Developed the IT departmental structure and Information Systems architecture.
- Guided the company in the IT investments and transformations of the IT infrastructure and operational procedures, necessary to achieve the PCI certification.
- Oversaw the reviews and responses of all IT audits performed by our clients
- Developed a culture of respect and trust within the IT organization that maintained a motivated and company loyal IT workforce.
- Oversaw successful integrations with companies in the Fortune 100 group that exceeded client expectations.

Information Technology Manager 2007-2011

Feedback, S.R.L.

- Supervised and maintained the operations of the IT infrastructure.
- Tracked and controlled of the IT Budget.
- Supervised the quality controls of the in-house developed software.
- Supervised and controlled security in the network infrastructure.
- Designed and controlled the Disaster Recovery annual plan testing.
- Responsible for the purchase of technology equipment.
- Enforced the compliance of security policies within the company.
- Oversaw the implementation of technology projects.

Technology Support Engineer 2005-2007

Feedback, S.R.L.

• Designed, implemented and supported the IT infrastructure.

Software Analyst 1997-2005

Tricom S.A.

 Analyzed and implemented software changes in the telecom call routing engine, that served millions of households' wireline and cellphone customers in the Dominican Republic market.

EDUCATION

Microsoft Certified Professional

Microsoft® Certified IT Professional: Enterprise Administrator

Master's in Marketing 2002-2004

 Instituto Tecnológico de Santo Domingo (INTEC), Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science 1996-2001

APEC University, Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic